<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE section [
<!ENTITY % entities SYSTEM "../../common/entities.ent">
%entities;
<!ENTITY IMAGEDIRPDF "../../common/images">
<!ENTITY IMAGEDIRHTML "images">
]>
   
<section xml:id="c-bulk_extract-top-edOrg"
    xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" 
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    
    <title>Top Level Education Organization Extract</title>
    
    <para>
        An education organization is considered as top level if it
        doesn't have any parent education organization. For example
        a State Education Agency can be a top level education organization
        for a tenant. 
    </para> 
    <para>
        Top level education organization extract is a special case. 
        The extract contains only the private data that belongs to that
        education organization. It will not have any data that belongs
        to its descendant education organizations (unlike other education
        organization extracts). This is applicable to both full and delta
        extracts.
    </para>
    <para>
        Changes in the education organization heirarchy within a tenant may
        change the contents of an education organization's extract file.
    </para>
     <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    If a top level education organization adopts a parent,
                    it ceases to be treated as top level and will be treated
                    as any other education organization for the purposes of Bulk Extract.
                    The extracts generated after this update for this 
                    education organization will include the data associated with its 
                    descendant education organizations.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    If an education organization loses all of its parent education organizations,
                    it will be treated as a top level education organization. The extracts
                    generated for this education organization after this update will cease
                    to include data associated with it's descendant education organizations.
                </para>
            </listitem>
     </itemizedlist>               
    
</section>
