<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE section [
<!ENTITY % entities SYSTEM "../../common/entities.ent">
%entities;
<!ENTITY IMAGEDIRPDF "../../common/images">
<!ENTITY IMAGEDIRHTML "images">
]>
   
<section xml:id="c-bulk_extract-encryption"
    xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" 
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    
    <title>Encryption for Bulk Extract Operations</title>
    
    <para>
        When applications call a bulk extract endpoint, a client 
        certificate is requested during the TLS (Transport Layer Security) 
        handshake. The certificate provided by the client is compared 
        against the certificate stored in the inBloom API service for 
        that application. Applications performing bulk extract operations 
        require an X.509 certificate using a 2048-bit RSA key. This 
        example command, using the open source OpenSSL utility, creates 
        an X.509 certificate and associated private key. 
    </para> 
    <para>
        <emphasis>WARNING:</emphasis> The TLS connection for bulk extract 
        endpoints must propagate all the way to the API/bulk extract node 
        and must not terminate at the load balancer/nginx.
    </para>
    <para>
        Applications performing bulk extract operations need an X.509 
        certificate using a RSA:2048 key. This example command creates 
        the X.509 certificate and the private key pair. 
    </para>
    <programlisting><![CDATA[openssl req -x509 -nodes -days 3650 -newkey rsa:2048 -keyout privateKey.key -out certificate.crt]]></programlisting>
    <para>
        The following information is true for the above example. 
        The variables can be modified as needed for different results.
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                The certificate is valid for 3650 days (10 years).
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                <filename>certificate.crt</filename> - 
                The self-signed X.509 certificate is output to this 
                filename.
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                <filename>privateKey.key</filename> - 
                The generated private key is output to this filename.
            </para></listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                With the "-nodes" flag, the private key is not encrypted, 
                so precautions should be taken in its handling (installation 
                in, and use by, the application).
            </para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
        The certificate must be provided to inBloom for installation 
        into the API service prior to generation of bulk extracts 
        for a given client application, and thus prior to attempted 
        retrieval of any extracts using these API endpoints.
    </para>
    
</section>
