<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE section [
<!ENTITY % entities SYSTEM "../../common/entities.ent">
%entities;
<!ENTITY IMAGEDIRPDF "../../common/images">
<!ENTITY IMAGEDIRHTML "images">
]>
   
<section xml:id="c-dashboard-customization-tutorial-profile_pages"
    xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" 
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    
    <title>Profile Pages</title>
    
    <para>
        Assuming you are looking at the dashboard following
        <xref linkend="t-how_to_upload_dashboard_customizations"/>,
        click the name "Matt Sollars" in the list view to open the profile 
        page for that student.
    </para>
    <para>
        The customization points of a profile page 
        are the title and contents of the tabs shown in the profile view. 
        Tabs can display a sequence of panels and grids. For example, the 
        "Middle School Overview" tab is the first tab that the user sees 
        when clicks on the name of a student. That tab is composed of one 
        panel and one grid. The following is the JSON for that tab.
    </para>
    <programlisting><![CDATA[{
    id:"tab8",
    name:"Middle School Overview",
    type:"TAB",
    condition:{
        (removed for brevity)
    }, 
    items:[
        {
            id:"contactInfo",
            type:"PANEL"
        }, 
        {
            id:"enrollmentHist",
            name:"Student Enrollment Panel",
            type:"GRID"
        }
    ]
}]]></programlisting>
    <para>
        In the above configuration, note that there is no indication of 
        the data to be provided. The dashboard relies on the default 
        behavior of that component to determine what entities and fields 
        to include. All available component IDs are covered in the sample
        provided for the tutorial, and they are defined in
        <xref linkend="c-dashboard-customization-reference"/>. 
        Use the "condition" array for any tabs that you would like to 
        preview; in this case, do this by making the tab available to the 
        8th grade or by navigating to a grade and student that makes sense 
        for that ID.
    </para>
    <para>
        In places where the "listOfStudents" component is used on the list 
        page, the column headings can be customized. That is not the case for
        the components that can be used in tabs. In most cases, the column 
        names displayed are the entity field names. Also, formatters in in 
        table cells are not available other than for "listOfStudents".
    </para>
    <para>
        Other than "listOfStudents", the "assessmentHist" component provides 
        some ability to constrain what data is shown. You can extend this 
        component so that the type of assessments to be displayed 
        (the Assessment Family) can be specified in the JSON:
    </para>
    <programlisting><![CDATA["assessmentHistAPE":{
    id:"assessmentHistAPE",
    parentId:"assessmentHist",
    type:"GRID",
    name:"Test History : AP English",
    data:{
        cacheKey:'assessmentHistAPE',
        params:{
            assessmentFamily:"AP.AP Eng"
        }
    }
}]]></programlisting>
    
</section>
