<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE section [
<!ENTITY % entities SYSTEM "../../common/entities.ent">
%entities;
<!ENTITY IMAGEDIRPDF "../../common/images">
<!ENTITY IMAGEDIRHTML "images">
]>
   
<section xml:id="c-how_ingestion_processes_data"
    xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" 
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    
    <title>How the Ingestion System Processes Data</title>
    
    <para>
        While processing an ingestion job, the ingestion system is responsible 
        for generating a changeset to represent the changes to the
        &PRODUCTABBR; data store. This <emphasis>changeset</emphasis> is an
        object that indicates what should change in the data store in order to
        bring the data up-to-date. It includes both what to add to the data 
        store and what to change about existing data in the data store.
    </para>
    <para>
        While creating the changeset, the ingestion system must resolve
        entity references in the XML. This includes both entities within the
        same ingestion job and to previously ingested entities.
    </para>
    <para>
        The matching algorithm for resolving entities relies on a combination 
        of each entity's fields to distinguish between insert and update 
        operations in the &PRODUCTABBR; data store. For entities with unique 
        tenant-wide identifiers (Student, Teacher, Staff, and Parent), the 
        <varname>stateUniqueId</varname> attribute is used to uniquely match 
        each ingested entity with the one already in the data store. If a 
        match is found, the operation is an update. Otherwise, it is an insert.
    </para>
    <para>
        Association entities are handled similarly. Newly added association 
        entities are checked against existing association entities referring 
        to the same objects in the data store. If the references match up, the
        new association is considered an update. Otherwise, it is an insert. 
    </para>
    
</section>
