<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE section [
<!ENTITY % entities SYSTEM "../../common/entities.ent">
%entities;
<!ENTITY IMAGEDIRPDF "../../common/images">
<!ENTITY IMAGEDIRHTML "images">
]>
   
<section xml:id="c-ingestion_security"
    xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" 
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    
    <title>Ingestion Security</title>
    
    <para>
        Security concerns for ingestion users include how those users
        authenticate with the landing zone, and how data is encrypted during 
        while uploading files and downloading logs.
    </para>
    
    <section xml:id="c-ingestion_security-authentication">
        <title>Authentication</title>
        <para>
            The FTP server for the landing zone authenticates each ingestion 
            user against the &PRODUCTABBR; directory. The ingestion user signs
            in to the landing zone from an FTP client using normal 
            authentication (username/password) and secure protocols and ports
            (SFTP/SSH). These credentials should match one of the &PRODUCTABBR;
            user accounts with the ingestion user role for that tenancy. 
            These accounts are created and managed by the &PRODUCTABBR; 
            administrators for that tenancy.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section  xml:id="c-ingestion_security-authorization">
        <title>Authorization</title>
        <para>
            The &PRODUCTABBR; CEM maintains an internal mapping between
            landing zones, tenants, and education organizations. An ingestion 
            user role covers one or more tenancies, typically associated with
            some point in the education organization hierarchy. Thus, as an 
            ingestion user, you can only access the landing zones and upload 
            data for the tenancies in which you have the ingestion user role.
        </para>
        <para>
            An administrative account, including an ingestion user, inherits
            tenant and education organization associations when that account
            is created. These associations will not change as a result of any
            subsequent changes to that information in the &PRODUCTABBR;
            directory. Thus, if any important identifying information changes
            for an ingestion user, an administrator for that user's tenancy
            should delete those ingestion user accounts and create new ones with
            the desired information. This identifying information includes a
            name referenced in the user's username (such as "jsmith" becoming
            "jjones").
        </para>
    </section>
    
    <section  xml:id="c-ingestion_security-encryption">
        <title>Encryption</title>
        <para>
            To protect 
            <glossterm linkend="def-pii">personally identifiable information (PII)</glossterm>, 
            the ingested files containing student data are encrypted during 
            transmission and storage, and that data is only delivered to 
            &PRODUCTABBR; applications using a secure network protocol. 
        </para>
    </section>
    
</section>
