<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE section [
<!ENTITY % entities SYSTEM "../../common/entities.ent">
%entities;
<!ENTITY IMAGEDIRPDF "../../common/images">
<!ENTITY IMAGEDIRHTML "images">
]>
   
<section xml:id="c-ingestion_sequence"
    xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" 
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    
    <title>Ingestion Sequence</title>
    
    <para>
        The following is the sequence of events that happen when ingesting
        data for the &PRODUCTABBR; data store. See &PRODUCTABBR; ingestion
        documentation for details about the files involved and how to create
        and use them:
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
	<listitem>
	    <para>
		Preparation:
	    </para>
		<orderedlist>  	
		<listitem>
		<para>
		 When a new tenancy comes on board the inBloom operator creates the tenancy.
		</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
					   inBloom operator will create the first administrator account that serves that tenancy.  From this point on, additional administrator accounts can be created by any existing administrator account (tenant administrators).  
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
					Tenant administrator creates their own landing zone.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
	</listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                A user creates a .zip archive file containing one control file
                and one or more of XML data files.
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                A user uses an sFTP client to upload the .zip archive file to
		the landing zone for the target tenancy.  The sFTP server 
		for Production is &PRODFTPSERVER;. Login credentials match those of the tenant administrator's inBloom login.
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                The ingestion system picks up the .zip archive and creates a
                corresponding ingestion job.
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                The ingestion system parses and validates the .zip archive.
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                The ingestion system parses and validates the control file
                within the .zip archive.
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                The ingestion system validates the XML files within the .zip
                archive.
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                The ingestion system parses those XML files and creates objects 
                from the data. The details about this part of the process
                are described in
                <xref linkend="c-how_ingestion_processes_data"/>.
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                The ingestion system continues to process the data objects
                until all data is processed and all changes are persisted to 
                the &PRODUCTABBR; data store.
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                The ingestion system adds log files for the ingestion job and
                its individual XML files to the landing zone for access by
                ingestion users. The log files contain errors, warnings, 
                statistics, and other status information.
            </para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>
        If any part of handling an ingestion job fails, then some or all of
        the data may not be persisted to the &PRODUCTABBR; data store. See
        <xref linkend="c-ingestion_logs"/> for details on how to determine
        where failures happened and what to do about them.
    </para>
    
</section>
