<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE revhistory [
<!ENTITY % entities SYSTEM "../common/entities.ent">
%entities;
]>

<revhistory xml:id="docs-administrator-revhistory"
    xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    
    <revision>
        <revnumber>1.2.72</revnumber>
        <date>3/19/2013</date>
        <revdescription>
            <para>
                Added Aggregate Viewer user role to the list of 
                default user roles.
            </para>
            <para>
                The Contextual Authorization Rules section was 
                reorganized for clarity.
            </para>
            <para>
                Updated sections on ingestion to refer to trim out instructions
                beyond configuring the landing zone and, instead, refer to 
                the new ingestion guide for how to prepare and ingest data.
            </para>
        </revdescription>
    </revision>
    <revision>
        <revnumber>1.2.73</revnumber>
        <date>4/13/2013</date>
        <revdescription>
            <para>
                There were no revisions in this document for the 1.2.73 release.
            </para>
        </revdescription>
    </revision>
    <revision>
        <revnumber>1.2.74</revnumber>
        <date>4/17/2013</date>
        <revdescription>
            <para> There were no revisions in this document for the 1.2.74 release. </para>
        </revdescription>
    </revision>
    <revision>
        <revnumber>1.3.75</revnumber>
        <date>4/30/2013</date>
        <revdescription>
            <para> Added information for bulk ingestion.</para>
        </revdescription>
    </revision>
    <revision>
        <revnumber>1.3.76</revnumber>
        <date>5/15/2013</date>
        <revdescription>
            <para>Removed chapter on CVS file conversion tool for
            ingestion; the tool is not currently actively
            maintained.</para>
        </revdescription>
    </revision>
    <revision>
        <revnumber>1.4.77</revnumber>
        <date>5/29/2013</date>
        <revdescription>
            <para>No changes were made to this document for this release.</para>
        </revdescription>
    </revision>
    <revision>
        <revnumber>1.5.78</revnumber>
        <date>6/12/2013</date>
        <revdescription>
            <para>No changes were made to this document for this release.</para>
        </revdescription>
    </revision>
    <revision>
        <revnumber>1.6.79</revnumber>
        <date>6/26/2013</date>
        <revdescription>
            <para>Updated chapter on integrated authentication to include
            a new check performed during the authentication process:
            check the value of "staffClassification", under
            "staffEdOrgAssignmentAssociation" in the user's record
            in the inBloom data store.</para>
            <para>
               Information has been added around the new default role, Student. Much of the content around roles and permissions is updated to reflect
               this new role. Also included are the current authorization rules for users logging in as a student.
            </para>
        </revdescription>
    </revision>
    <revision>
        <revnumber>1.7.80</revnumber>
        <date>7/07/2013</date>
        <revdescription>
            <para>
                Revised the section covering the default user roles to include
                the role group concept, the permissions assigned by role group,
                and the newly added roles for each role group.
            </para>
            <para>
                Added new information to section covering how &PRODUCTABBR;
                determines a user's permissions, and updated the screenshot
                for the custom roles tool showing the default configuration.
            </para>
            <para>
                Added new authorization rules for users logging in as a student.
            </para>
        </revdescription>
    </revision>    
    <revision>
        <revnumber>1.8.81</revnumber>
        <date>7/19/2013</date>
        <revdescription>
            <para>
                Information has been added around the new default role, Parent. Much of the content around roles and permissions is updated to reflect
                this new role. Also included are the current authorization rules for users logging in as a parent.
            </para>
        </revdescription>
    </revision>   
    <revision>
        <revnumber>1.9.82</revnumber>
        <date>8/2/2013</date>
        <revdescription>
            <para>
                Added a note in the section about security even logs to draw
                attention to the securityEvents resources in the REST API.
                Also cleaned up the table covering what security events are
                logged.
            </para>
        </revdescription>
    </revision>
    <revision>
        <revnumber>1.11.86</revnumber>
        <date>9/27/2013</date>
        <revdescription>
            <para>
                The new Staff and Teacher contexts, and their affect on
                determining user permissions, were added in the chapters
                covering user rights and roles.
            </para>
            <para>
                Contextual authorization chapters were updated to reflect
                the Staff and Teacher contexts, and to remove program and
                cohort rules that were not applicable.
            </para>
            <para>
                Updated Manage Applications section to reflect changes to
                application authorization procedures.
            </para>
        </revdescription>
    </revision>
    <revision>
        <revnumber>1.12.88</revnumber>
        <date>10/25/2013</date>
        <revdescription>
            <para>
                Updated Manage Applications section to reflect changes to
                application authorization procedures.
            </para>
            <para>
                Ability for LEA Admins to authorize applications has been restored.  Hosted
                Admins (SEA and LEA) can authorize any and all education organizations
                in their education organization hierarchy using a tree control on the
                Application Authorization Dashboard.
            </para>
			<para>
				Updated SecurityEvents API call documentation to refer to updated Developer Guide.  Updated the descriptions of Logged Events.
            </para>
        </revdescription>
    </revision>
    <revision>
        <revnumber>1.12.89</revnumber>
        <date>11/08/2013</date>
        <revdescription>
            <para>
                Bulk extract documentation update.
            </para>
            <para>
                Removed notes for application delegation as
                the functionality no longer exists.
            </para>
            <para>
                Removed mentions of targetEdOrg because that property is no longer being used.
                Removed mention of log files as they are inaccessible.
            </para>
        </revdescription>
    </revision>
    <revision>
        <revnumber>1.12.90</revnumber>
        <date>11/22/2013</date>
        <revdescription>
            <para>
                Federated users may now be given the right to view security events through the API (through the SECURITY_EVENT_VIEW
                right). This gives them the ability to use the /api/rest/securityEvent and /api/rest/securityEvent/{id} resources
                for education organizations within their purview.
            </para>
        </revdescription>
    </revision>
    <revision>
        <revnumber>1.13.91</revnumber>
        <date>12/6/2013</date>
        <revdescription>
            <para>
                Updated example of API's SAML metadata.
            </para>
            <para>
                Added instruction for obtaining certificate used by API for digital signing.
            </para>
            <para>
                Added description and screenshot of the addition of the Artifact Resolution Endpoint
                and IDP Source ID fields to the Manage Realm system tool.
            </para>
            <para>
                Added instruction for obtaining and adding API's client certificate.
            </para>
            <para>
                Added description about encrypted assertion for artifact binding.
            </para>
            <para>
                Added section describing new APP_AUTHORIZE right for federated users.  Updated Manage Applications section to reflect
                new ability of federated users to authorize applications.
            </para>
        </revdescription>
    </revision>
    <revision>
        <revnumber>1.14.92</revnumber>
        <date>12/20/2013</date>
        <revdescription>
            <para>
                Updated description of public data bulk extract.
            </para>
            <para>
                Added description of top level education organization extract.
            </para>
            <para>
                Added description about encrypted assertion for post.
            </para>
            <para>
                Updated description of default user roles.
            </para>
        </revdescription>
    </revision>
    <revision>
        <revnumber>1.15.94</revnumber>
        <date>1/21/2014</date>
        <revdescription>
            <para>Added description of configuration details for Data Browser.</para>
        </revdescription>
    </revision>
    <!--revision>
        <revnumber>&CURRENTRELEASEREVISION;</revnumber>
        <date>&CURRENTRELEASEDATE;</date>
        <revdescription>
            <para>No changes were made to this document for this release.</para>
        </revdescription>
    </revision-->
    
</revhistory>

        
