<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE chapter [
<!ENTITY % slc_entities SYSTEM "../common/entities.ent">
%slc_entities;
]>

<chapter 
    xml:id="doc-10f4c2b3-93b4-4dce-adae-1a93feecc49c" 
    xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" 
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    
    <info>
        <title>&PRODUCTABBR; Data Ingestion</title>
    </info>
    <para>
        <glossterm linkend="def-data_ingestion">Data ingestion</glossterm> is 
        the process of uploading new and updated data to the &PRODUCTABBR; 
        Data Store. Ingestion consumes data from one or more source files 
        placed in an FTP server location and adds the data to the 
        &PRODUCTABBR; Data Store. There may be applications designed to add, 
        view, and edit one record at a time, but ingestion is designed to 
        handle several dozen, to several thousand, data records at one time. 
        Ingestion Users have access to the system tools necessary for 
        ingestion.
    </para>
    
    <section xml:id="doc-9aafba21-be2e-4cdc-b3f3-3d86c4cdcbd7">
        <title>How Ingestion Works</title>
        <para>
            The ingestion process works like this:
        </para>
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Files are prepared for ingestion and placed in a 
                    <glossterm linkend="def-landing_zone">landing zone</glossterm>. 
                    The landing zone is an FTP server location where you can 
                    upload files to be ingested to the
                    &PRODUCTABBR; Data Store. 
                </para>
                <para>
                    &PRODUCTABBR; administrators can set up one or more of 
                    these landing zones to serve a single data store. For 
                    instructions on how to set up and manage landing zones, see
                    <xref linkend="doc-ae2a0aaf-7960-4272-a5ea-abffb0973e74"/>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> 
                    &PRODUCTABBR; checks for files in the configured 
                    <glossterm linkend="def-landing_zone">landing zone</glossterm>. 
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> 
                    &PRODUCTABBR; kicks off the data ingestion process, 
                    working through the files in the landing zone.  
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> 
                    When ingestion is complete, &PRODUCTABBR; administrators 
                    can confirm that the newly ingested data is available in 
                    the &PRODUCTABBR; Data Store. The &PRODUCTABBR; 
                    Data Browser is an administration tool designed for this 
                    purpose. 
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
    </section> <!-- END of Data Ingestion Overview -->
    
    <section xml:id="doc-fe6b4f03-127c-45f2-b975-0c66ad9e43d9">
        <title>Ingestion Users</title>
        <para>
            An &PRODUCTABBR; administrator does not need to be an 
            Ingestion User to prepare data for ingestion or to use the 
            ingestion validation and conversion tools. However, that user 
            must have the Ingestion User role to ingest data into the 
            &PRODUCTABBR; Data Store. The Ingestion User creates landing zones 
            and uploads files to any landing zone associated with their
            tenancy.
        </para>
        <para>
            Any SEA, LEA, or Realm Administrator can be assigned the 
            Ingestion User role, or an administrator can be designated as an 
            Ingestion User only. For more information about user roles see 
            <xref linkend="doc-84cff820-10a6-4968-96b7-eb0bde31ca95"/>.
        </para>
        <para>
            An Ingestion User account cannot be moved between tenancies. The 
            relationship between the account and the landing zone for a 
            tenant persists, so an Ingestion User could inadvertently upload 
            data for his new tenant to the old one. Therefore, if an Ingestion
            User moves to a new tenancy, the old account for the user should 
            be deleted and a new account should be created. 
        </para>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="doc-ae2a0aaf-7960-4272-a5ea-abffb0973e74">
        <title>Creating and Managing Landing Zones</title>
        <para>
            The landing zone is an FTP server location where you can upload
             files to be ingested to the &PRODUCTABBR; Data Store. To create 
             and manage landing zones, you need an &PRODUCTABBR; administrator
             account with the
             <glossterm linkend="def-ingestion_user">Ingestion User</glossterm>
             role.
        </para>
        <para>
            Use the following steps to create landing zones:
        </para>
        <procedure>
            <step>
                <para> Log in to &PRODUCTABBR; with your Ingestion User administrator account. </para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    Click <guibutton>Admin</guibutton>.
                </para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    Click <guibutton>Create Landing Zone</guibutton>.
                </para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    Click <guibutton>Create</guibutton>.
                </para>
                <para>
                    After you click <guibutton>Create</guibutton>, you'll 
                    receive an email with further instructions for ingesting 
                    data using your new landing zone. For a detailed look at 
                    these instructions, see 
                    <xref linkend="doc-53e3a1af-a134-428e-a0e0-428bbd70dd20"/>.
                </para>
            </step>
        </procedure>
        <note>
            <title>Landing Zones for Sandbox Developers</title>
            <para>
                Application developers who are using a Sandbox development
                environment have a different experience when creating and
                using landing zones. For documentation about landing zones and
                data ingestion in a Sandbox, see developer documentation at
                <link xlink:show="new" xlink:href="&DEVWEBSITE;">&DEVWEBSITE;</link>.
            </para>
        </note>
        <!-- Questions to answer in future revisions:
             What configuration options do I have for landing zones?
             What are the approximate minimum and maximum processing times for data ingestion in a theoretical scenario?
             What conditions will affect the speed of data ingestion and the validity of the content once saved to the data store?
        -->
    </section> <!-- END of Creating and Managing Landing Zones -->
    
    <section xml:id="doc-53e3a1af-a134-428e-a0e0-428bbd70dd20">
        <title>Ingesting Data for the &PRODUCTABBR; Data Store</title>
        <para>
            Data ingestion starts by making a secure file transfer to a 
            landing zone. To do this, upload files using an FTP client 
            to the a landing zone configured for the target tenancy.
            The results of the ingestion job are shown in messages
            in a series of log files, which you can download from the
            same landing zone.
        </para>
        <para>
            The uploading and downloading is the easy part of ingestion.
            The more complex and time-consuming task is preparing data
            for ingestion. Data must be provided in XML files compliant 
            with the &INGESTIONSCHEMANAME; schema, which
            is the Ed-Fi Core &EDFIVERSION; schema plus the 
            &PRODUCTABBR; extension schema. A control file must list
            important information about the XML files to be ingested, and
            all the files must be bundled into a single .zip archive for
            uploading.
        </para>
        <para>
            &COMPANYABBR; produces an ingestion guide that includes all the
            details you need to prepare data for ingestion. It also provides
            additional information on how ingestion works and how to
            troubleshoot ingestion jobs based on log file messages.
        </para>
    </section> <!-- END of Ingesting Data for the inBloom Data Store -->
    
    <xi:include href="../modules/concepts/c-ingestion-sif.xml" />
        
</chapter>
