<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE chapter [
<!ENTITY % entities SYSTEM "../common/entities.ent">
%entities;
]>

<chapter xml:id="doc-dfd3b13b-bce1-431a-93ef-8acc6563cff7"
    xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" 
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    
    <title>Security and Administration Designations</title>
    <para> To better understand the roles, permissions, and other &PRODUCTABBR; security information
        for &PRODUCTABBR; users that are described in <xref linkend="doc-3e1677bd-a02f-44a0-9c73-4eaaa1e1b064"
        />, it is necessary to be familiar with the security and administration designations. </para>
    <section xml:id="doc-37d742c3-43b7-4f1e-a471-61be1ffe7e6c">
        <title>Tenant and Realm</title>
        <para>
            &PRODUCTABBR; administration is often described in terms of a
            <firstterm>tenant</firstterm> or a <firstterm>realm</firstterm>:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para> A <glossterm linkend="def-tenant">tenant</glossterm> is a single set of
                    self-consistent data that is logically isolated within the &PRODUCTABBR; Secure
                    Data Service. A tenant logically corresponds to an <glossterm
                        linkend="def-education_organization">education organization</glossterm>,
                    such as a state, county, or district school system. &PRODUCTABBR; was designed
                    so that within a tenant, records should readily transfer when a student or staff
                    member changes schools, even if it a transfer between districts under the same
                    state. The highest tenant level that the infrastructure is designed to manage is
                    that associated with a single state education agency (SEA). </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    A <glossterm linkend="def-realm">realm</glossterm> is a 
                    designation used to describe the context within which a
                    digital user's authentication is valid. In other words, 
                    a realm corresponds to the level at which identity services
                    exist. If a district provides its own identity services, 
                    that district can serve as a realm. If a state is 
                    providing identity services, then the state is a realm. 
                    If there is a group of districts within a state that have 
                    a shared identity service, then the organization that 
                    groups those districts together is a realm. 
                    In &PRODUCTABBR;, the highest available realm is a
                    state education agency (SEA).
                </para>
                <para> 
                    User IDs, defined by the realm, are only guaranteed to be 
                    unique within the context of a single tenant. For example, 
                    multiple tenants could contain the user ID 
                    <guilabel>tmifune</guilabel>, but &PRODUCTABBR; does not
                    consider <guilabel>tmifune</guilabel> from one tenancy to
                    be the same user as <guilabel>tmifune</guilabel> from 
                    another tenancy. To avoid data conflicts, a realm should 
                    not serve multiple tenants.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="doc-822b31de-b272-4598-bf46-3a9766b7fb1c">
        <title>Federated and Hosted</title>
        <para>
            &PRODUCTABBR; user and administrator roles are described as being 
            either
            <firstterm>federated</firstterm> or <firstterm>hosted</firstterm>:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para> A <glossterm linkend="def-federated">federated</glossterm> user is a user
                    that authenticates using an identity provider that is maintained by an education
                    agency, whether at the state, county, or district level. This identify provider
                    (IDP), typically a directory service like LDAP, is where the <glossterm
                        linkend="def-realm">realm</glossterm> is defined. Since the IDP is external
                    to &PRODUCTABBR;, user roles in &PRODUCTABBR; must be customized and mapped to
                    correspond to the user roles in the IDP. This should be done before data is
                    added to the &PRODUCTABBR; Secure Data Service, whether through <glossterm
                        linkend="def-data_ingestion">data ingestion</glossterm> or through the REST
                    API). Administrator and developer documentation for &PRODUCTABBR; cover the
                    tools and procedures for managing user roles and rights. </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> 
                    A <glossterm linkend="def-hosted">hosted</glossterm> user 
                    is a user created in the 
                    <glossterm linkend="def-hosted_directory">&PRODUCTABBR; hosted directory service</glossterm>.
                    The hosted directory service is one of the services
                    deployed and managed as part of the &PRODUCTABBR;. The
                    role of these hosted users is to serve as administrators 
                    for &PRODUCTABBR;; thus, they're referred to as 
                    <glossterm linkend="def-inbloom_administrator">&PRODUCTABBR; administrators</glossterm>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    
</chapter>

        
