<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter [
<!ENTITY % entities SYSTEM "../common/entities.ent">
%entities;
]>
<chapter xml:id="doc-14ebb50a-f3f1-4c7b-8d94-d872310d0219" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0">
    <title>&COMPANYABBR; Data Classification</title>
    <para> This chapter covers the different categories of data that &PRODUCTABBR; uses to classify
        data. Access to data is determined by a user's rights and their context with the entity.
        The data itself is categorized into three distict categories that influences if and how it
        can be accessed by a user.</para>
    <section xml:id="doc-1a553c59-9ecc-45bd-89e7-e094e3938fb8">
        <title>Global Entities</title>
        <para>Global entities are entities that are truly global within the context of a tenant.
            Assessments is an example of a global entity. An assessment, such as the SAT, is not
            tied to a specific education organization or section (an optional association is
            possible). Assessments are considered to be global. because they cannot be associated
            with a context. The following entities are considered to be global:</para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>/assessments</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>/competencyLevelDescriptors</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>/learningObjectives</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>/learningStandards</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        <para>Global data is managed using the READ_PUBLIC and WRITE_PUBLIC rights.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="doc-bc2265de-8669-4406-af79-65b92d26e688">
        <title>Public Entities</title>
        <para>Public entities are entities that are associated to a smaller scope within a tenant.
            For example, a course is considered a public entity. Courses can be defined at the State
            Education Agency, Local Education Agency, or School-level. Though the scope is variable,
            anyone with an association to any education organization within the hierarchy should be
            able to see the course, making it public information. The following entities are
            considered to be public:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>/courses</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>/courseOfferings</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>/educationOrganizations</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>/graduationPlans</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>/gradingPeriods</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>/programs</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>/schools</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>/sections</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>/sessions</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>/studentCompetencyObjectives</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>Public data is managed using the READ_PUBLIC and WRITE_PUBLIC rights.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="doc-603b8e11-5c94-42d9-975f-a530fc02f68e">
        <title>Protected Entities</title>
        <para>Any data that is restricted using access control is considered protected.Protected
            data is managed using rights other than READ_PUBLIC and WRITE_PUBLIC. Depending on the
            particular data, a user either requires READ_GENERAL or READ_RESTRICTED to read
            protected data. WRITE_GENERAL or WRITE_RESTRICTED is required to write protected
            data.</para>
    </section>
</chapter>
