<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE chapter [
<!ENTITY % entities SYSTEM "../common/entities.ent">
%entities;
]>

<chapter xml:id="doc-9e33db6a-9515-4dce-829e-4ab009bb29ea"
    xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" 
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    
    <title>Contextual Authorization: Teachers</title>
    
    <para>
        The rules in this section apply specifically to users that are 
        associated with the Teacher context configured for user roles. 
    </para>
    
    <section xml:id="c-contextual_authorization-teacher-required_assoc">
        <title>Teacher Entity Must Have Certain Associations</title>
        <para>
            Part of determining access to data includes confirming that a 
            Teacher has a current TeacherSchoolAssociation. To confirm
            that a TeacherSchoolAssociation is current, every Teacher 
            must have a StaffEducationOrgAssignmentAssociation. 
            A Teacher without a StaffEducationOrgAssignmentAssociation is 
            considered invalid data.
        </para>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="c-contextual_authorization-teacher-assoc_to_student">
        <title>Teacher Context Relies on Section, Cohort, or Program</title>
        <para>
            <emphasis role="bold">RULE:</emphasis>
            <emphasis>A Teacher has a context to present Student data based on
            a current Section, Program, or Cohort to which 
            the Teacher is currently associated (meaning that the 
            <varname>endDate</varname> of the association is not in the past). 
            </emphasis>
        </para>
        <para>
            Teacher can access data based on current 
            Section, Program, or Cohort associations. 
            The following diagram shows the entities involved.
        </para>
        <figure xml:id="figure-security-teacher-context-resolution">
            <title>Teacher Security Context Resolution</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject role="html">
                    <imagedata align="center" 
                        fileref="images/security-teacher-context-resolution.png" 
                        width="750px" scalefit="1"/>
                </imageobject>
                <imageobject role="fo">
                    <imagedata align="center" 
                        fileref="../common/images/security-teacher-context-resolution.png" width="7in"
                        scalefit="1"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emphasis role="bold">RULE:</emphasis> 
            <emphasis>Teacher has context to historical student data as it 
            does to present data. Student historical data means current 
            data about the student's past, such as past grades. This rule
            applies even if the data lives ourside the Teacher's 
            educationOrganization hierarchy. The Teacher rights to that data 
            is based on their rights to the student entity.
            </emphasis>
        </para>
        <para>
            While Teacher has context to this historical data,
            the Teacher user's rights specify access to the following 
            historical data entities:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Attendance
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    CourseTranscript
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    DisciplineAction
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    DisciplineIncident
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Grade
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Parent
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    ReportCard
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    StudentAcademicRecord
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    StudentAssessment
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    StudentCohortAssociation
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    StudentCompetency
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    StudentDisciplineIncidentAssociation
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    StudentGradebook
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    StudentParentAssociation
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    StudentProgramAssociation
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    StudentSchoolAssociation
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    StudentSectionAssociation
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>
            The historical data access rule is an exception to the 
            general rule which states that the Teacher's context is within 
            their own educationOrganization hierarchy.
        </para>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="c-contextual_authorization-teacher-expired_assoc">
        <title>Teacher Context Expires When Associations End</title>
        <para>
            <emphasis role="bold">RULE:</emphasis> 
            <emphasis>Teacher A does not have access to Staff B or Teacher B
            if Staff B or Teacher B is no longer associated with Teacher A's 
            educationOrganization.</emphasis>
        </para>
        <para>
            Teacher cannot access data for teachers or staff that are no 
            longer associated with their educationOrganization.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emphasis role="bold">RULE:</emphasis>  
            <emphasis>A Teacher does not have access to a Student
            that is enrolled in the teacher's past Section, Cohort, or
            Program unless the (system-level configurable) grace period is 
            greater than the time the section have ended.
            </emphasis>
        </para>
        <para>
            The Teacher cannot access a student who was a past, but not current,
            part of a Section, Cohort, or Program that Teacher is currently
            associated with. Instead, Teachers lose access to former students 
            after a grace period expires. For example, if Linda Kim's sections 
            ended 2 days ago  (this means she does not currently teach that 
            section) and the grace period is 10 days, then Linda Kim should 
            still have access to her former student Jimmy for another 8 days.
        </para>
    </section>

</chapter>


        
