<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE chapter [
<!ENTITY % entities SYSTEM "../common/entities.ent">
%entities;
]>
    
<chapter xml:id="doc-d6c53933-f760-494d-a52e-e1c68513eda2"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" 
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    
    <title><phrase>Managing User Roles and Rights</phrase></title>
    
    <para> &COMPANYABBR; assigns user roles and rights based on the roles configured in the
        &PRODUCTABBR;. You should ensure that the roles configured in &PRODUCTABBR; align with those
        associated with users in the &PRODUCTABBR; Secure Data Service. In Production, those user
        roles are managed by the identity provider (IDP) for an <glossterm
            linkend="def-education_organization">education organization</glossterm>. </para>
    <para> 
        In &PRODUCTABBR;, you can create, edit, and delete roles and role 
        groups using the Create Custom Roles system tool. For each role 
        group, you can assign one or more roles and select one or more 
        rights to associate with that group. 
    </para>
    <para> 
        &PRODUCTABBR; provides several default role groups. However, if the 
        roles in your education organization's IDP do not already match the 
        roles and rights contained in these role groups, you will need to 
        map new or existing roles from this tool to the roles that IDP. 
    </para>
    <para>
        <xref linkend="figure-admin_tools-role_mapping-default-annotated"/> shows the Create Custom
        Roles system tool. </para>
    <figure xml:id="figure-admin_tools-role_mapping-default-annotated">
        <title>Create Custom Roles Page</title>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject role="fo">
                <imagedata align="center"
                    fileref="../common/images/admin_tools-role_mapping-default.png" width="8.0in"
                    scalefit="1"/>
            </imageobject>
            <imageobject role="html">
                <imagedata align="center" 
                    fileref="images/admin_tools-role_mapping-default.png" 
                    scalefit="1"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>
        The following is a description of the interface features shown:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                <emphasis role="bold">Group Name</emphasis> - Name of the role group to which
                one or more roles belong. Rights are assigned by group, rather than by role, and one
                or more roles can be managed under a single group. The default groups are Aggregate
                Viewer, Leader, IT Administrator, and Educator. </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                <emphasis role="bold">Roles</emphasis> – Names of the roles associated with the
                group. These should map to the roles within your education organization's identity
                provider. The default roles are Aggregate Viewer, Leader, IT Administrator, Educator
                and Student. </para>
            <note>
                <para>
                    Each role name must be unique across all role groups. In 
                    other words, you cannot have two roles with the same name, 
                    and the same role cannot occur in two or more role groups.
                </para>
            </note>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                <emphasis role="bold">Rights</emphasis> – Permissions that a 
                group has. Permissions relate to the ability to read and write
                individual data categories as outlined in 
                <xref linkend="doc-7eda3ec2-ce9b-472f-9255-7e8206fdcd7a"/>. 
                You can modify the rights for a role group at any time.
                Note that staff roles also require a context right. That means 
                that each staff role should have one or both of the 
                <varname>STAFF_CONTEXT</varname> and
                <varname>TEACHER_CONTEXT</varname> rights. 
                Context rights are not applicable to students and parents.
            </para>
        </listitem>
       <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Rights for Self</emphasis> - This section allows you to assign different rights to a user for Self 
                than they would have for other entities for which they have context. As an example, a teacher can have access to their own private data
                without also requiring the permission to see the private data for other teachers they have context with.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Admin Role</emphasis> – This is a role, also referred to
                as the isAdminRole flag, that should only be applied to groups that administer the
                system. By default, this role belongs to the IT Administrator.  A user with multiple
                roles assigned is only considered an administrative user if all of those roles have
                the <emphasis>isAdminRole</emphasis> marked as true.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                <emphasis role="bold">Action Buttons</emphasis> – This section displays the edit
                and delete (trashcan) buttons. When you click <guibutton>Edit</guibutton>, the group
                becomes editable. When you click <guibutton>Delete</guibutton>, the entire row is
                deleted. </para>
            <note>
                <para>
                    The default roles and role groups can be edited or deleted.
                    This allows you to modify their rights or to remove 
                    them completely from your &PRODUCTABBR; instance.
                </para>
            </note>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                <emphasis role="bold">Add Role Group</emphasis> – This button lets you create a
                new role group. This allows you to extend the roles beyond the four default roles
                that come standard in &PRODUCTABBR;. When you click this button, an editable row appears
                at the bottom of the table. See <xref
                    linkend="doc-9b8588a6-9672-4762-a1c4-9ed364d68e0b"/> for more details. </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                <emphasis role="bold">Reset to Defaults</emphasis> – This button restores your
                roles and rights to the &PRODUCTABBR; default roles and rights. </para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    
    <section xml:id="doc-9b8588a6-9672-4762-a1c4-9ed364d68e0b">
        <title>Adding a New Role Group</title>
        <para>
            If you want to extend the types of roles beyond &PRODUCTABBR;'s 
            default roles, you must create a new role group.
        </para>
        <para>
            To add a new role group:
        </para>
        <procedure>
            <step>
                <para>Log in to &PRODUCTABBR;.</para>
                <substeps>
                    <step><para>If you are logging into a Sandbox, click <guibutton>Administer my Sandbox</guibutton>.</para></step>
                </substeps>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>Click <guilabel>Admin</guilabel>.</para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>Click <guilabel>Create Custom Roles</guilabel> under System Tools.</para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    Click <guibutton>Add Role Group</guibutton> at the bottom 
                    of the page. An editable row appears at the bottom of 
                    the table.
                </para>
                <figure xml:id="figure-admin_tools-role_mapping-edit_mode">
                    <title>An Editable Row for a New Role Group<inlinemediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </inlinemediaobject><inlinemediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata
                                    fileref="../common/images/Updated%20Figure%209%20An%20Example%20of%20a%20New%20Role%20Group.png"
                                />
                            </imageobject>
                        </inlinemediaobject></title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject role="fo"/>
                        <imageobject role="html">
                            <imagedata align="center" 
                                fileref="images/admin_tools-role_mapping-edit_mode.png" 
                                scalefit="1"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    Enter the name of the group. The role group should have 
                    a logical name for the roles within the group. 
                    For example, <guilabel>School Board Personnel</guilabel>.
                </para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    Enter a name for the role that you want to add for the 
                    group. When you are satisfied with the name, click 
                    <guibutton>Add</guibutton>.
                </para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Once added, the role will appear below the role 
                            name input. You can click 
                            <guibutton>X</guibutton> to delete the role.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            You can add multiple roles for a single role group. 
                            For example, <guilabel>Superintendent</guilabel> 
                            and <guilabel>School Board Member</guilabel>.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    Select a right to give to the role group. 
                    Click <guibutton>Add Right</guibutton>. 
                </para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Once added, the right will appear below the 
                            <guilabel>Right Name</guilabel> drop-down menu. 
                            You can click <guibutton>X</guibutton> to 
                            remove the right.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            You can grant multiple rights to a single role 
                            group.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <figure xml:id="figure-admin_tools-role_mapping-schoolboard_example">
                    <title>An Example of a New Role Group<inlinemediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </inlinemediaobject><inlinemediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata
                                    fileref="../common/images/Updated%20Figure%209%20An%20Example%20of%20a%20New%20Role%20Group%20v2.png"
                                />
                            </imageobject>
                        </inlinemediaobject></title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject role="fo"/>
                        <imageobject role="html">
                            <imagedata align="center" 
                                fileref="images/admin_tools-role_mapping-schoolboard_example.png" 
                                scalefit="1"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
            </step>
            <step><para>If you want the members of the group to have administrative rights, check the <guilabel>Admin
                        Role</guilabel> box.</para>
       <!--         <para>You should also check this box when making a student custom role group if you
                    want to be able to see the student log in information in the Data Browser. </para> -->
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    When you're finished, click <guibutton>Save</guibutton> 
                    to create the role group. The role group appears at the 
                    bottom of the table.
                </para>
            </step>
        </procedure>
    </section>    
    
    <section xml:id="doc-3f3a0352-95d9-486e-9dd1-e53ebbe2b570">
        <title>Multiple Local IDP Roles Mapped to One &PRODUCTABBR; Role</title>
        <para>
            It is possible to map multiple roles from your local IDP to a single &PRODUCTABBR; role. In this case, the user only receives the rights that are included in all of the roles from the local IDP. This prevents users from viewing unauthorized data.
        </para>
        <para>
            For example, if you are a principal in school A and a teacher in school B, you will only have the rights associated with the teacher for both school A and school B.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="docs-1f287266-28e7-4bbd-b46d-6a216699494e">
        <title>Managing Custom Roles for Multiple Realms</title>
        <para>
            Education organizations can manage custom roles independently for 
            multiple realms. If you are administering multiple realms, 
            clicking Create Custom Roles directs you to list of the
            available realms. To manage the custom roles for a particular 
            realm, click the Custom Roles button to modify the roles for that 
            realm. After accessing the Custom Roles page for the specific 
            realms, modify the custom roles as you would in a single realm
            environment.
        </para>
        <figure xml:id="figure-realm-select">
            <title>A Multiple Realm Example</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject role="fo">
                    <imagedata align="center"
                        fileref="../common/images/realm-select.png" width="7.5in"
                        scalefit="1"/>
                </imageobject>
                <imageobject role="html">
                    <imagedata align="center" 
                        fileref="images/realm-select.png" 
                        scalefit="1"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
    </section>
</chapter>
