<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE chapter [
<!ENTITY % entities SYSTEM "../common/entities.ent">
%entities;
]>

<chapter xml:id="doc-54ba0efa-dd34-4b0f-b911-caf7a8c94065"
    xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" 
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    
    <title>Contextual Authorization Rules</title>
    
    <para> Context refers to the combined conditions under which a user or application exists
        relative to the data in the &PRODUCTABBR; Secure Data Service. This starts with user roles
        and permissions, and extends to other conditions that affect context. This includes the
        education organization to which the user is assigned, whether the application was granted
        permission to that education organization, and the date and time the user is attempting to
        access data. </para>
    <para>
        The &PRODUCTABBR; system determines a user's access to data based on
        that context. A user who has effective permission to access data, with 
        all these conditions in place, may be said to have "context with"
        that data. The permissions themselves may be referred to as
        "contextual access."
    </para>
    <para>
        Contextual authorization is the set of rules that &PRODUCTABBR; uses
        to determine a user's contextual access. The rules rely on the following
        user characteristics:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para> Each user is associated with a single and unique entity in the &PRODUCTABBR;
                Secure Data Service: <varname>Staff</varname>, <varname>Teacher</varname>,
                    <varname>Parent</varname>, or <varname>Student</varname>. </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                Each staff or teacher user has a context of 
                <varname>Staff</varname>, <varname>Teacher</varname>, or both 
                based on how the &PRODUCTABBR; administrator has configured 
                custom user roles and contexts for the system.
            </para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
        This section describes the authorization rules that govern the 
        context-based authorization for the 
        <glossterm linkend="def-federated">federated</glossterm> users
        of an education organization (those configured in &PRODUCTABBR;
        to authenticate by that organization's IDP), enforced through 
        the &PRODUCTABBR; REST API. These rules 
        are used in conjunction with the permissions associated with a user's 
        role to determine access to data, or the user's 
        <glossterm  linkend="def-effective_permissions">effective permissions</glossterm>.
        For a more complete understanding of how &PRODUCTABBR; determines 
        effective permissions see 
        <xref linkend="doc-016d8db7-11ec-4bf0-9028-1f5a6e81782b"/>. 
    </para>
    <para> Throughout this chapter are references to <glossterm linkend="def-entity"
            >entities</glossterm> from the &PRODUCTABBR; Secure Data Service. For a comprehensive
        list of entities, organized by <glossterm linkend="def-data_domain">data domain</glossterm>
        and broken down by <glossterm linkend="def-attribute">attributes</glossterm>, visit <link
            xlink:show="new"
            xlink:href="https://inbloom.org/sites/default/files/docs-developer/data_model.html"
            >https://inbloom.org/sites/default/files/docs-developer/data_model.html</link>. </para>
    
    <section xml:id="doc-8d0237d2-0f35-4f73-a51b-33a6ddce7bf9">
        <title>Global Authorization Rules</title>
        <para>
            While most of the business rules for contextual authorization 
            relate to specific entities or contexts, the following rules
            apply to all users:
        </para>
        <para>
            <emphasis role="bold">RULE:</emphasis>
            <emphasis>Any context resolution in the &PRODUCTABBR; model starts with the context of
                the user's role in an educationOrganization in the &PRODUCTABBR; Secure Data
                Service. Every successfully authenticated user (through federation) must be
                associated with at least one staff role in the Secure Data Service in order to
                access any data in &PRODUCTABBR;.</emphasis>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emphasis role="bold">RULE:</emphasis> 
            <emphasis>No user from a 
            <glossterm linkend="def-tenant">tenant</glossterm> 
            should be able to access any data from another tenant.</emphasis>
            There is no exception to this rule.
        </para>
        <para>
            A tenant acts as a permissions boundary. Even if two 
            districts (A and B) belong to a same State S, if they are 
            deployed as separate tenants, no users from A will be able to
            access B. In addition, if State S is not in a tenant with 
            any of the districts, state users will not be able to access 
            the district's data. 
        </para>
        <para>
            For more about tenants, 
            see <xref linkend="doc-37d742c3-43b7-4f1e-a471-61be1ffe7e6c"/>.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emphasis role="bold">RULE:</emphasis>
            <emphasis>Every authenticated user in &PRODUCTABBR; can access 
            the information about any educationOrganization that exists in 
            that user's (own) 
            <glossterm linkend="def-tenant">tenancy</glossterm>.</emphasis>
        </para>
        <para>
            Education organization information is public. For example, if 
            School A and School B are schools in State S, and State S is 
            on-boarded as a single tenant, then a teacher from School A can
            access the School B name, address, and other entities, even 
            though School B does not belong in the same education organization
            as School A. However, users can only have write access to 
            data within their own education organization.
        </para>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="doc-1a553c59-9ecc-45bd-89e7-e094e3938fb8">
        <title>Global Entities</title>
        <para>
            Global entities are entities that are truly global within the 
            context of a tenant. Every user in the tenant has access to 
            them.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emphasis role="bold">RULE:</emphasis>
            <emphasis>Everyone in a tenant has access to global 
            entities.</emphasis>
        </para>
        <para>
            Assessments is an example of a global entity. An assessment, 
            such as the SAT, is not tied to a specific education organization
            or section (an optional association is possible). Since assessments 
            are considered to be global, they cannot be associated with a
            context. The following entities are considered to be global:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>/assessments</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>/competencyLevelDescriptors</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>/courseOfferings</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>/courses</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>/educationOrganizations</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>/gradingPeriods</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>/graduationPlans</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>/learningObjectives</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>/learningStandards</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>/programs</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>/schools</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>/sections</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>/sessions</para>
            </listitem>
             <listitem>
                <para>/studentCompetencyObjectives</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <note>
            <para>
                These entities are protected with the 
                READ_PUBLIC and WRITE_PUBLIC rights.
            </para>
        </note>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="doc-18125e10-2ed3-4f25-9e5a-0e6f2c0e477c">
        <title>Orphan Entities</title>
        <para>
            An Orphan Entity is an 
            <glossterm linkend="def-entity">entity</glossterm> that has no 
            <glossterm linkend="def-association">association</glossterm> 
            (yet) with other entity. For example, a Student entity was 
            created, but it was not yet associated with an EdOrg. 
        </para>
        <para>
            <emphasis role="bold">RULE:</emphasis>
            <emphasis>The creator of an orphan entity has context 
            with (can access) that data entity.</emphasis>
        </para>
        <para>
            Once the creator associates the entity with something else 
            in the system, the creator's ability to view that entity 
            goes back to the regular access rules. In addition, the
            next rule applies.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emphasis role="bold">RULE:</emphasis>
            <emphasis>You can only associate two entities if you have 
            context with both entities.</emphasis>
        </para>
        <para>
            Thus, it is not possible to create a student and then associate
            that student to a school or section that you do not have context 
            with.
        </para>
    </section>
        
</chapter>
