<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE chapter [
<!ENTITY % slc_entities SYSTEM "../common/entities.ent">
%slc_entities;
<!ENTITY IMAGEDIR "../common/images">
]>
   
<chapter xml:id="doc-f4f8305d-43e2-4641-956e-ab66be20557b"
    xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" 
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    
    <title>Deploy Platform: Directory Service</title>
    
    <para>
        The user authentication data store for the SimpleIDP uses OpenLDAP. This is described in the
        user authentication and landing zone authentication sections of this document.
    </para>
    <para>
        OpenLDAP can be installed via various package management systems. We  
        recommend installing the current release version of OpenLDAP from source.  
        This is due to known issues with replication in the currently available packages 
        for RedHat Enterprise Linux.
    </para>
    <para>
        An installation of at least two OpenLDAP servers is recommended with N-Way 
        Multi-Master Replication.
    </para>
    <para>
        OpenLDAP installation documentation can be found at: 
        <link xlink:show="embed" xlink:href="http://www.openldap.org/doc/admin24/install.html">http://www.openldap.org/doc/admin24/install.html</link>
    </para>
    <para>
        OpenLDAP documentation on replication can be found at: 
        <link xlink:show="embed" xlink:href="http://www.openldap.org/doc/admin24/replication.html">http://www.openldap.org/doc/admin24/replication.html</link>
    </para>
    <para>
        OpenLDAP documentation on password policy controls can be found in Section 12.10 of 
        the OpenLDAP Administration Guide.  The specific section can be found here: 
        <link xlink:show="embed" xlink:href="http://www.openldap.org/doc/admin24/overlays.html#Password%20Policies">http://www.openldap.org/doc/admin24/overlays.html#Password Policies</link>
    </para>
    <para>
        OpenLDAP documentation on SSL setup can be found at: 
        <link xlink:show="embed" xlink:href="http://www.openldap.org/doc/admin24/tls.html">http://www.openldap.org/doc/admin24/tls.html</link>
    </para>
    <para>
        As password controls are placed in the OpenLDAP server, the ppolicy overlay, along 
        with the ppolicy_hash_cleartext (olcPPolicyHashCleartext) and password-hash 
        (olcPasswordHash) configuration options must be used for secure password storage, 
        in addition to ACLs in the directory that control and protect access to passwords, 
        and overall directory write access.
    </para>
    <para>
        <note>
            <para>A non-manager account MUST be utilized for all interaction between the software
                and the LDAP directory because the OpenLDAP Manager account does not have the
                "ppolicy" overlay applied to its interactions.  Therefore. a generic account object
                must be created and granted elevated privileges through the Access/olcAccess method.
                This allows that non-manager account to Read/Write across the Organizational Unit
                that the software is configured to utilize. </para>
        </note>
    </para>
    <para>
        OpenLDAP configuration changes:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                olcSizeLimit - The default OpenLDAP query size limit of 500
                must be relaxed. Suggested value for this option is 
                "unlimited". Two functions of the system may be impacted if 
                the number of &PRODUCTABBR; Hosted Users (including
                Operators, SEA Administrators, LEA Administrators, 
                Ingestion Users, and Application Developers) exceeds this 
                value: &OPERATORROLE;'s account management tool, and 
                developer account registration.
            </para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    
</chapter> 

