<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE chapter [
<!ENTITY % slc_entities SYSTEM "../common/entities.ent">
%slc_entities;
]>
    
<chapter xml:id="doc-9aafba37-be2e-4cdc-b3f3-3d86c4cdcba0"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" 
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    
    <title>Data Ingestion: Overview</title>
    
    <para>
        <glossterm linkend="def-data_ingestion">Data ingestion</glossterm>,
        sometimes simply called <firstterm>ingestion</firstterm>, is one of
        two ways to add data to the &PRODUCTABBR; Data Store. Ingestion
        is designed to handle several dozen to several thousand data records
        at one time. This is different from &PRODUCTABBR; web applications 
        designed to add, view, and edit one record at a time.
    </para>
    <para>
        Data ingestion consumes data from one or more source files.
        The process works like this:
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                &PRODUCTABBR; checks whether there are files in a
                configured <glossterm linkend="def-landing_zone">landing zone</glossterm>.
                The landing zone is an FTP server location where you can upload
                files to be ingested to the &PRODUCTABBR; Data Store.
            </para>
            <para>
                &PRODUCTABBR; administrators can set up one or more of these landing 
                zones to serve a single data store. For instructions on how to 
                set up and manage landing zones, see
                <xref linkend="doc-ae2a0aaf-7960-4272-a5ea-abffb0973e74"/>.
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                &PRODUCTABBR; kicks off the data ingestion process, working
                through the files in the landing zone. For details about how
                to ingest data, see
                <xref linkend="doc-53e3a1af-a134-428e-a0e0-428bbd70dd20"/>.
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                When ingestion's complete, &PRODUCTABBR; administrators can confirm
                that the newly ingested data is available in the &PRODUCTABBR;
                Data Store. You can use the Data Browser administration tool 
                that's for this purpose.
            </para>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>
        Use the links in the bulleted list above to access additional
        ingestion-related documentation.
    </para>
    <section>
        <title>Prerequisites to Ingestion</title>
        <para>Before you can ingest data, you must:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Have the appropriate user role that will allow you to
                        ingest data. &PRODUCTABBR; provides an <emphasis>Ingestion
                            User</emphasis> role.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Be authorized to work with data 
                    for a specific educational organization.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Have access to a configured 
                    landing zone. A landing zone is an FTP server location 
                    that will store your XML files while they are being 
                    ingested.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>
            If you don't already have a landing zone, 
            the next step will be to set up your landing zone. If you already
            have your landing zone set up, please skip to 
            <xref linkend="doc-6b9d21e0-0d62-4ab7-996d-9b40bccdd422"/>.
        </para>
    </section>
    
</chapter>
