<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE chapter [
<!ENTITY % slc_entities SYSTEM "../common/entities.ent">
%slc_entities;
]>
    
<chapter xml:id="doc-301d3570-8120-4bd1-ae93-59f5a03a38e9"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" 
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    
    <title>Deploy &PRODUCTABBR; Applications: Data
        Browser</title>

    <para>
        The sections
        that follow cover preparing for, installing, and configuring the Data Browser as part of the
        applications in &PRODUCTABBR;. </para>
    
    <section xml:id="doc-2e56b691-b5ad-41ef-86bf-5b4152c20a59">
        <title>Data Browser: What You Need to Know Before Deployment</title>
        <para> 
            The Data Browser is a web application that allows the end user 
            to traverse data that is available through the RESTful API. 
            The Data Browser is a read-only application, meaning that it
            cannot be used to modify any of the data viewed.
        </para>
        <para>
            Designated administrators for education organizations will likely 
            use the Data Browser to validate ingested data. As described
            in &PRODUCTABBR; administrator documentation, the Data Browser 
            is listed as one of the available applications from the 
            administrator home page for users with permission to use it. 
            Data Browser users are part of the &PRODUCTABBR; hosted user
            directory and in the federated directories for state and local
            education agencies.
        </para>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="doc-351e172e-84c1-4288-a86f-eef36196a678">
        <title>Data Browser: Installation</title>
        <para>
            Installation for the Data Browser requires the following:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    A Rails server
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Ruby Version Manager (rvm)
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Ruby 2.0.0
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Bundler Ruby Gem <code>`gem install bundler`</code>
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para> A user account that can be authenticated by the operator identity provider
                    with group membership in "&PRODUCTABBR; Administrators". </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para> Use the following procedure to install the Data Browser application for
            &PRODUCTABBR;. These steps assume that you'll be locating the application into a
                <filename>$RAILS_HOME</filename> folder, where
                <filename>$RAILS_HOME/public</filename> is your <filename>$WWWROOT</filename>
            folder: </para>
        <procedure>
            <step>
                <para>
                    Extract the admin software package to <filename>$RAILS_HOME</filename>.
                </para>
                <programlisting><![CDATA[
tar xvzf -C $RAILS_HOME databrowser-package.tgz
                            ]]></programlisting>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    Change your current directory to <filename>$RAILS_HOME</filename>.
                </para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    Execute the following commands to install all of the pre-requisite 
                    Ruby gems and compile the assets:
                </para>
                <programlisting><![CDATA[
bundle install --deployment
bundle exec rake assets:precompile
                            ]]></programlisting>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    Modify the <filename>$RAILS_HOME/config/deploy/team.rb</filename> file to define 
                    the name of the environment. This will allow multiple configurations 
                    to be placed in the <filename>config.yml</filename> file, although only one 
                    configuration can be used at a time.
                </para>
                <programlisting><![CDATA[
server "databrowser.example.com", :app, :web, :db, :primary => true
set :rails_env, "production"
                            ]]></programlisting>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    Create a configuration file that represents your 
                    environment, named <filename>$RAILS_HOME/config/config.yml</filename>.
                    Use the following example as a guide.
                </para>
                <programlisting><![CDATA[
production:
api_base: https://api.example.com/api/rest
redirect_uri: https://databrowser.example.com/callback
portal_url: https://portal.example.com/headerfooter-portlet/api/secure/jsonws/headerfooter
client_id: 10CharIden
client_secret: 48CharacterRandomSecret
show_edorg_table: true
                            ]]></programlisting>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <code>api_base</code> - The URL where the application will need to connect 
                            to in order to work with the API, as well as direct the user 
                            for authentication.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <code>client_id</code> - A ten character random string [a-z|A-Z|0-9] that 
                            represents the application for authentication to the API service. <emphasis>Important:</emphasis> Be sure to use the encrypted client_id from step 5.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <code>client_secret</code> - A forty eight character random string [a-z|A-Z|0-9] 
                            that is used as a shared secret between the API and the application. <emphasis>Important:</emphasis> Be sure to use the encrypted client_secret from step 5.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <code>show_edorg_table</code> - true/false 
                            Setting to determine whether or not to show the count table on the Education Organization 
                            pages. This table will get displayed when Education Organiztions are shown. Even in a
                            list of Education Organizations, each will have it's own table.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    Ensure that your configuration matches that of the API configuration file, 
                    which should be bootstrapped into the Mongo database. Once verified, and 
                    the configuration is located in the Mongo database within 
                    the application collection, you are ready to proceed.
                </para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>
                    Access the server webroot with a web browser. You will be re-directed to the API, 
                    which will re-direct you to the configured IDP.  If validated correctly, 
                    you will then be redirected back to the API, and then back to the Data Browser 
                    web application. In order to test the functionality of the application, you must
                    be logged in to the Data Browser as a user that has access to some ingested data.
                </para>
            </step>
        </procedure>
    </section>
    
    <!--
    <section xml:id="doc-b742ede9-210c-4f6e-878b-d03dde668d35">
        <title>Data Browser: Configuration</title>
        <para>
            FIXME... more to come
        </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="doc-c9acdf96-c2a1-46e5-9796-1458eee9f09c">
        <title>Data Browser: Troubleshooting During Deployment</title>
        <para>
            FIXME... more to come
        </para>
    </section>
    -->
    
</chapter>
