<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE chapter [
<!ENTITY % slc_entities SYSTEM "../common/entities.ent">
%slc_entities;
<!ENTITY IMAGEDIR "../common/images">
]>

<chapter xml:id="doc-82271e02-dc46-4cf0-b371-b6bd229ab970"
    xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" 
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    
    <title>Release 6.1 to 6.3 Database Transformation</title>
    <para>The 61to63DBMigration.sh script is a utility that performs a sequence of of updates and
        deletions to the sli database in order to facilitate the move to the per-tenant database
        model. <note>
            <para> The 61to63DBMigration.sh script is coded to operate only on a database named
                “sli”. Deviation from this name in an environment requires modification of the
                script.  </para>
        </note></para>
    <para>The end result is that the core “sli” database contains only key collections with metadata
        for the &PRODUCTABBR; application stack to operate, while the newly created tenant databases
        house the required key records. </para>
    <para>All ingested data is purged by this process and will need to be re-ingested by the tenant
        or Sandbox user, while preserving key tenant or Sandbox user configuration post
        re-ingestion.</para>
    <para>The following actions are performed by this process:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem><para>Addition of a hashed dbName field to each tenant collection entry.</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>Migration of the tenant’s customRole, custom_entitites, applicationAuthorization, and adminDelegation collection entries from the sli database to the new tenant database.</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>Deletion of all collections that contain tenant data from the sli database.</para></listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
    <section>
        <title>Executing the Database Transformation</title>
        <para>These steps are the upgrade sequence of events in which the 61to63DBMigration.sh
            script is executed. Since exact operator processes, data volumes, and environmental
            differences can vary, the software operator should be consulted to identify an
            appropriate overall downtime estimation. </para>
        <procedure>
            <step>
                <para>Stop all API, Ingestion, and SimpleIDP services.</para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>Complete a backup of the:</para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem><para>SLI database</para></listitem>
                    <listitem><para>LDAP</para></listitem>
                    <listitem><para>sli.properties configuration
                        file</para></listitem>
                </itemizedlist> 
                <para>in order to ensure that there is a point in time snapshot of the
                    configuration, and data that can be restored should an issue be encountered and
                    environment rollback is deemed necessary.</para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>Complete an upgrade to Mongo 2.2., if not already completed, to ensure that
                    all running mongo databases and mongos services are 2.2.0.</para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>Execute the 61to63DBMigration.sh script from a instance with a running mongos
                    service. </para>
                <para>In the WGen test environment, with an sli database size of approximately 2GB,
                    execution of this script took less than one minute.</para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>Disable the mongo balancer. Open the mongo command line while connected to a
                    mongos service, and execute the following commands on the mongos command line: </para>
            <substeps>
                <step><para>use config</para></step>
                <step><para>db.settings.update( { _id: "balancer" }, { $set : { stopped: true } } , true );</para></step>
            </substeps>
                <note><para>Additional information on this step is covered in the Release 6.3 Environmental Specification document.</para></note>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>Restart all mongos services.</para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>Deploy Release 6.3 software in accordance with the 6.3 Environment
                    Specification and Release Notes.</para>
            </step>
            <step><para>Restart API, Ingestion, and Simple IDP services.</para></step>
        </procedure>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>End User Post Transformation Process</title>
        <para>Once the data transformation is completed, the Tenant/Sandbox/Developer Administrative
            users must do the following:</para>
    <procedure>
        <step><para>Re-provision the Landing Zone utilized by visiting “Provision Landing Zone” in the Admin interface.</para></step>
        <step><para>Re-Ingest the desired data set.</para></step>
        <step><para>Once ingestion is finished, developers need to re-approve the ingested Educational
                    Organizations to utilize the registered applications.</para>
            <note>
                    <para>In a Production environment, this item is performed only by
                        Developers.</para>
                </note></step>
    </procedure>
    </section>
</chapter>