<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE chapter [
<!ENTITY % slc_entities SYSTEM "../common/entities.ent">
%slc_entities;
]>

<chapter xml:id="doc-c16da7d8-5385-4c51-8809-d4bb5e6148f5" xml:base="."
    xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>inBloom’s core functionality, the Secure Data Services (SDS), is a multiuser,
        transaction-based Database. The inBloom SDS is run either as Software as a Service (SaaS)
        where inBloom manages the operation or an Operator model, where a provider opts to maintain
        their own instance of the software.</para>
    <para>An inBloom managed deployment offers is a secure, cloud-hosted data store designed for
        states and districts. An Operator instance is responsible for maintaining the service with
        the same expectations for performance, security, and availability as inBloom has for our
        managed instance. Operators are encouraged to align with an established level of technical
        and business standards to offer stakeholders a secure and optimal experience and are
        expected not to change the provided inBloom APIs so that applications can use them no matter
        which instance of the service their customers opt to use.</para>
    <para>Whether a SaaS or an Operator model, the inBloom SDS securely maintains data about state
        and district’s organizational structure, schools, and employees, as well as information on
        student enrollment, biographical and achievement data. In implementing inBloom’s SDS
        solution, states and districts load data to the SDS data store through high-volume data
        interfaces.</para>
    <para>The goal of inBloom’s SDS is to provide a level of data interoperability that allows
        states, districts, schools and teachers to tailor resources and learning applications to
        their local and individual needs securely by providing an API. The Secure Data Service API
        makes the process of sharing individual learning tools and strategies easier and more
        efficient. Overcoming these data interoperability barriers is the ultimate objective of
        inBloom’s SDs and are core to enabling the products and strategies that drive personalized
        learning in the classroom.</para>
    <para>This Runbook provides procedures, requirements and recommendations for installing,
        configuring, running, and upgrading the inBloom Secure Data Services (SDS). Additionally,
        this Runbook should be used to understand the practices and procedures for the efficient use
        of inBloom’s SDS.</para>
    <sect1 xml:id="doc-ff943989-e3b8-439e-96a1-ee48f7f34c2e">
        <title>Scope</title>
        <para> This guide is intended for system engineers, system operators, and system
            administrators, each of whom are responsible for specific tasks in the process of
            standing up an inbloom deployment.. </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1 xml:id="doc-6d545148-58cc-4e41-be34-8b8e5dd3ecb8">
        <title>Typographic Conventions</title>
        <para> The following table describes the typographic conventions that this document uses to
            enhance semantic meaning. </para>
        <table xml:id="table-6c79a49e-8c8e-4128-80a1-71b4b8817fe2">
            <title>Typographic Conventions</title>
            <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="firstCol" colwidth="1*"/>
                <colspec colname="secondCol" colwidth="2*"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry>Format</entry>
                        <entry>Used for</entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>
                                <guibutton>Bold</guibutton>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para> GUI controls that the user interacts with such as buttons, folder
                                tabs, icons, and so forth. </para>
                            <para>
                                <emphasis role="bold">Example</emphasis>: Check the <guibutton>Not
                                    Available</guibutton> check box. </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>
                                <emphasis>Italic</emphasis>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para> First use of words, emphasis, document titles, and variable text. </para>
                            <para>
                                <emphasis role="bold">Example</emphasis>: See the <citetitle>REST
                                    API Reference</citetitle>. </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>
                                <code>Monospace</code>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para> Code examples, file names, field names. </para>
                            <para>
                                <emphasis role="bold">Example</emphasis>: Apply the following patch
                                to <filename>/etc/sysconfig/iptables</filename>. </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para> Line break in code blocks </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para> When a string of code on a single line is too long to display in
                                the code block shown; standard UNIX convention for code wrapping </para>
                            <para>
                                <emphasis role="bold">Example</emphasis>: </para>
                            <programlisting><![CDATA[
command -optionOne sampleValue -optionTwo sampleValue \
-anotherOption sampleValue
                                    ]]></programlisting>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
    </sect1>
    <sect1 xml:id="doc-24dd0bbc-6635-4ead-afab-a16086bdf4e2">
        <title>Security </title>
        <para>All Operators should be prepared to ensure compliance with industry security best
            practices and procedures. Operators are encouraged to meet refined criteria for security
            and privacy of data as well as systems performance and have complete access to inBloom's
            security toolsets and support. </para>
        <para>inBloom recommends that an Operator of inBloom’s technology implement a complete
            information security program, including preventive, detective, and reactive controls
            that cover technical, physical, and administrative security commensurate with security
            controls that inBloom currently has in place. </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Assumptions</title>
        <para> The following guidelines provide the recommended hardware and software necessary to
            sustain a delivery model that will support multiple customers at scale. Further
            identification of critical path to Operator success can be defined with assistance from
            inBloom staff during an initial review of ecosystem assets at potential Operator sites.
            The following guidelines provide system requirements to execute a full scale deployment
            of inBloom Secure Data Services. In addition to the following lists of hardware,
            software, and technologies, inBloom can advise on personnel required to staff, implement
            and maintain an Operator environment, as well as provide optimal customer care to
            stakeholders. </para>
        <para>inBloom recommends that staff involved in the deployment of inBloom Secure Data
            Service have 3-5 years experience with Linux  and with load balancing and distributed
            file systems. </para>
        <para/>
        <sect2>
            <title> Hardware </title>
            <para>Operator hardware needs will vary depending on the volume of data and number of
                students your Operator program aims to support. Maintaining an efficient system will
                require the use of numerous physical or virtual servers of a caliber that would meet
                typical business operations for handling large datasets and frequent, concurrent
                connections by external parties via the internet. Operators are expected to have N+1
                redundancy in an active-active configuration for all servers, as well as appropriate
                firewall and intrusion detection, and load balancing technologies. An Operator can
                expect to provide hardware to enable and maintain the following components of the
                inBloom service offering: <emphasis role="bold"/></para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Database Servers</emphasis></para>
            <para>Database (Mongo 2.x)</para>
            <para>Database Config</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">API/Search Servers</emphasis></para>
            <para>Internet application interface (API)Search messaging queue - </para>
            <para>ActiveMQSearch Indexer - </para>
            <para>ElasticSearchSearch Processing/MessagingSearch Box - </para>
            <para>customer feeds to APIs</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Web/Application Servers</emphasis></para>
            <para>Web Server (Apache 2.2 / Tomcat / Java 1.6 / Ruby 2.0 / Rails 3.x)</para>
            <para>Data Browser</para>
            <para>Dashboard</para>
            <para>Portal (liferay)</para>
            <para>System Tools-admin authorization management for IT Admins</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">General Servers</emphasis></para>
            <para>File System (Gluster/NFS currently used)</para>
            <para>Firewall (ModSecurity)</para>
            <para>Identity Provider (SimpleIDP currently used)</para>
            <para>Federated directory service (LDAP)</para>
            <para>Learning Registry Node</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Customer Data Administration</emphasis></para>
            <para>Landing zone boxes</para>
            <para>Ingestion</para>
            <para>Bulk Extract </para>
            <para>File delivery system (SFTP/SSH</para>
            <para/>
       </sect2>
        <sect2> 
        <title>Software</title>
        <para>InBloom has applied a variety of software in the creation of its offerings. While not
                all of the software listed below may be required within a particular Operator
                instance, the inBloom Runbook best practices provides assistance with the
                installation and proper configuration of the software. An Operator can expect to
                install the following software to enable and maintain the inBloom service offering: </para>
            <para>MongoDB - Document database used to store education data and system
                configuration</para>
            <para>ActiveMQ - Messaging system for asynchronous processing</para>
            <para>Gluster - Distributed file system for batch-processing XML ingestion files</para>
            <para>ElasticSearch - Search software used for some search operations</para>
            <para>OpenLDAP - Directory server for configuration of system-wide tools and
                administrators</para>
            <para>Tomcat - Java application server for API and other applications</para>
            <para>Apache - Web server used for load balancing and firewall via mod security</para>
            <para>Linux - Host operating system, specifically Ubuntu 12.04</para>
            <para>Chef - Systems configuration tool (to manage policy and host
                configurations)</para>
            <para>Gazzang - Encrypts file systems to protect data at rest (MongoDB and
                GlusterFS)</para>
            <para>SSL - Certificate Management</para>
            <para>VPN - Management</para>
            <para>JumpBox - Security alerts</para>
            <para>Atlassian – Issue tracking and public backlog (JIRA, Confluence)</para>
        
        </sect2>
    </sect1>
</chapter>

        
